Let's talk about organizational governance frameworks there are three big things that we didn't know
when it comes to governance and frameworks.
Well first off what is governance frameworks on governance are the rules and enforcement of those rules
that govern the project or we govern the program or the organization as a whole.
Its the rules thats what you are and are not allowed to do in your organization or your project.
A framework is just the structure how its been created.
It gives some structure to the project.
So an example of that would be you have a project manager you have several different team leaders for
the different disciplines or technologies so you have a team lead for hardware.
If a team lead for data a team lead for software and so then you have your team members and they report
to the appropriate team lead and then those team leads and you communicate and talk to one another as
well.
So thats just an example of a framework that have to be that way.
Let's look at these three things that we need to know in regard to the organization in governance frameworks
governance as I mentioned defines what you can and cannot do in the organization that you as a PM cannot
sign a contract with a vendor.
You know that's pretty fair.
You have some governance there.
Its also how you operate within a system.
So how do you get a contract signed.
Well we have to go and fill out a form for procurement and talk about procuring these resources and
then the third point here is framework is that organizational structure.
Like I talked about in your project thats also the hierarchy and the framework that happens in the organization
as a whole.
So its what you can and can't do.
It's how you get things done and then it's the structure.
What are the boundaries and the different segments of the organization.
Some more things about governance frameworks rules and policies are always part of governance framework
the procedures for activity.
So how you install that fixture how you get resources how you do procurement.
So just the procedures that we have the cultural norms.
I worked in a place say as a consultant a few years ago where it was pretty normal Friday at about 12:30.
Just kind of people would drift off.
So it's just the cultural norm which just how they were.
Everybody love Friday.
Nobody scheduled the meeting for Friday afternoon.
And you guys out there there you know what I'm talking about.
All right systems and processes so how do you get things done.
So what's the procurement system what's the quality management system.
What's the process you go through to host a kickoff meeting.
So it's within the organization.
How you do work.
But then obviously that affects how you manage the project.
And then a framework influences how the objectives are set and achieve.
So you have the framework so one of the objectives sometimes we call them the KPI key performance indicators.
So what are your time your cost your scope or quality and your risk objectives so what are the thresholds
that tell you you're performing well or you need improvement risk Howze risk Moniteur to assess how
well you do risk identification.
How will you do qualitative and quantitative.
And then how will you monitor those risk and even risk responses as you move through the project.
Generally the higher the project priority the higher the framework of FX that risk management approach.
So a very low level project don't really care a whole lot about risk.
I mean there may be some issues there but generally a high priority project.
Then we are more adverse are our risk threshold is lower our acceptance or tolerance level for risk
diminishes and then some risk we always care about.
So you think about in construction or healthcare manufacturing or any of those disciplines where there's
a pure risk and danger were some that could get injured even on a low priority project we don't want
that to happen.
So we have a very high aversion to risk that our tolerance level is very low when it comes to pure risk.
Then how is your project performance optimize how will you get better in what you're doing.
Sudi have some coaching you have some trend analysis in your project sponsor give you some ideas or
some goals for each phase or quarter of your project.
OK so this is the big picture on governance and frameworks.
All right keep moving forward I'll see you in the next lecture.